<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<job-applications last-updated="2026-02-12">
  <application id="cvs-health-principal-enterprise-architect-2026">
    <company>CVS Health</company>
    <role>Principal Enterprise Architect</role>
    <location>US (not specified)</location>
    <salary-range>$144,200-$288,400 + bonus + equity</salary-range>
    <date-applied>2026-02-11</date-applied>
    <status>resume-generated</status>
    <resume-path>resumes/cvs-health-principal-enterprise-architect/resume.md</resume-path>
    <job-url></job-url>
    <notes>
      Principal Enterprise Architect driving innovation and platform strategy. Strong match: 20+ years enterprise architecture (since Allstate 2004), current AI platform design at McDonald's (10-layer architecture, CIO endorsement), 15+ years cloud platforms (GCP, Azure), complex integration experience (APIs, microservices, event-driven with Kafka/A2A/MCP), architecture governance (TOGAF, BIZBOK, Six Sigma), mentoring at scale (154 GCP Champs participants, 88 IBA program contributors). Key differentiator: hands-on builder-architect hybrid who designs target state AND builds working systems. Gaps: C4 model not explicitly claimed (mitigated by ArchiMate and equivalent diagram types—context, container, component); BComm not CS degree (mitigated by Diploma in Datametrics in Computer Science); no direct healthcare industry experience (mitigated by Allstate Financial adjacency, regulatory/compliance work, enterprise scale). Context: Senior/Executive seniority, Technical function, Enterprise company type.
    </notes>
    <keywords-matched>
      enterprise architecture, AI, Agentic AI, GenAI, APIs, microservices, event-driven architecture, cloud, target state architecture, north star architecture, architecture governance, standards, best practices, mentoring, coaching, POC, starter code, collaboration, influencing, coalition-building, non-functional requirements, performance engineering, data platforms, hybrid solutions, Agile, C4 equivalent
    </keywords-matched>
    <excitement-rating>HIGH</excitement-rating>
  </application>

  <application id="google-applied-ai-fsa-manager-2026">
    <company>Google Cloud</company>
    <role>Manager, Applied AI Field Solutions Architect</role>
    <location>Multiple US locations (NY, Atlanta, Austin, Chicago, Seattle, SF, etc.)</location>
    <salary-range>$177,000-$263,000 + bonus + equity</salary-range>
    <date-applied>2026-02-03</date-applied>
    <status>resume-generated</status>
    <resume-path>resumes/google-manager-applied-ai-fsa/resume.md</resume-path>
    <job-url></job-url>
    <notes>
      Manager role for Applied AI FSA team. Strong match: 7 years Google Cloud tenure, current agentic AI experience with MCP/Python, $1.5B pipeline achievement, 88-contributor program leadership. Gap: limited direct management (influence-based leadership). REVISED: Leadership + Sales emphasis per user request. Added: Intel TCO partnership, 40+ agents metric, Awards section, Director title for McDonald's.
    </notes>
    <keywords-matched>
      Google Cloud, agentic AI, multi-agent systems, Python, MCP, RAG, enterprise, C-suite, technical leadership, Field Solutions Architect
    </keywords-matched>
    <excitement-rating>HIGH</excitement-rating>
  </application>

  <application id="forrester-principal-analyst-2026">
    <company>Forrester Research</company>
    <role>Principal Analyst, AI-Enhanced Software Development</role>
    <location>US (Remote eligible, 30% travel)</location>
    <salary-range>Not specified (base salary range inclusive of all US geographies)</salary-range>
    <date-applied>2026-02-06</date-applied>
    <status>resume-generated</status>
    <resume-path>resumes/forrester-principal-analyst/resume.md</resume-path>
    <job-url></job-url>
    <notes>
      Career transition: practitioner to industry analyst. JD explicitly prefers 10+ years software dev leadership (director+). Strong match: AI architecture at McDonald's (350+ use cases, 22 patterns, 10 megatrend papers), research program leadership at Google (88 contributors, 12 industries), advisory work with research firms (8 engagements), conference speaking (RSA, Advisen, AON CTO), vendor evaluation (Stratozone acquisition). Gaps: no formal analyst title (mitigated by JD preference for practitioners), no Forrester Wave experience (mitigated by vendor evaluation work), limited press relationships. Context: Senior/Executive seniority, Executive/Thought Leadership function, Enterprise company type.
    </notes>
    <keywords-matched>
      AI-enhanced software development, research, AI agents, strategy, governance, cost optimization, KPIs, SDLC, consulting, advisory, thought leadership, cross-team collaboration, mentorship, business development, client engagement
    </keywords-matched>
    <excitement-rating>HIGH</excitement-rating>
  </application>

  <application id="pwc-director-data-analytics-engineering-2026">
    <company>PwC</company>
    <role>Director, Data and Analytics Engineering (AI/ML)</role>
    <location>US (not specified)</location>
    <salary-range>Not specified</salary-range>
    <date-applied>2026-02-11</date-applied>
    <status>resume-generated</status>
    <resume-path>resumes/pwc-director-data-analytics-engineering/resume.md</resume-path>
    <job-url>https://pwc.wd3.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/US_Experienced_Careers/job/Advisory-National-CT-I---AI-Engineer---Director_684871WD-1</job-url>
    <notes>
      Director-level role in Big Four consulting firm. Sets strategic direction for AI initiatives, oversees cloud-native ML platform delivery, mentors next generation. Strong match: currently Principal AI Architect at McDonald's (10-layer AI platform, 350+ use cases, CIO endorsement), 7+ years at Google Cloud ($1.5B pipeline, 88 contributors), consulting DNA (advisory, methodology creation, training at scale). Key JD requirement "10 years in AI/ML engineering, software development, OR technical leadership" satisfied via 20+ years technical leadership path. Gaps: ML/deep learning hands-on depth (nascent), no Master's degree (preferred not required), no direct ML engineer team management (mitigated by influence-based leadership model typical of consulting). Context: Senior/Executive seniority, Technical function, Enterprise company type. REVISED v2: Sharpened PwC consulting alignment in summary (consulting DNA, data-driven decision making). Added keyword coverage for scalable, cloud-native microservices, CI/CD pipelines, reliability/maintainability, responsible AI governance, innovative technologies, production systems. Reorganized skills section with AI/ML &amp; Data Engineering lead category and dedicated AI Governance &amp; Process category. Promoted responsible AI governance bullet. Expanded Earlier Career to highlight consulting practice leadership at Revere Group.
    </notes>
    <keywords-matched>
      AI/ML, machine learning, cloud-native, strategic direction, AI initiatives, cross-functional, Python, CI/CD pipelines, responsible AI, governance, mentoring, thought leadership, GCP, Azure, AWS, Kubernetes, production, large-scale, continuous improvement, knowledge sharing
    </keywords-matched>
    <excitement-rating>HIGH</excitement-rating>
  </application>

  <application id="figma-business-systems-architect-2026">
    <company>Figma</company>
    <role>Business Systems Architect (AI-Powered Internal Systems)</role>
    <location>US (Remote or SF/NY hubs)</location>
    <salary-range>$149,000-$260,000 USD</salary-range>
    <date-applied>2026-02-11</date-applied>
    <status>resume-generated</status>
    <resume-path>resumes/figma-business-systems-architect/resume.md</resume-path>
    <job-url></job-url>
    <notes>
      Business Systems Architect leading AI-powered internal systems and MCP (Model Control Plane) matrix design. Standout differentiator: Robin has hands-on MCP experience at Fortune 500 scale (McDonald's 10-layer AI platform) — extraordinarily rare in market. Strong match on enterprise architecture (20+ years), AI strategy (350+ use cases, 22 patterns), multi-model orchestration, vendor evaluation, cross-functional leadership (88 contributors), and architecture governance. Gap: no direct Salesforce/NetSuite/Workday/Notion experience — mitigated by MarTech SaaS stack integration (mParticle, Braze, SessionM, Dynamic Yield) and ServiceNow/Gravitee integration patterns. Compliance frameworks (SOC2/GDPR/ISO 27001) are nice-to-haves, addressed by AI compliance work with legal counsel and Google Cloud security positioning. Context: Senior/Executive seniority, Technical function, Scale-up company type.
    </notes>
    <keywords-matched>
      AI, MCP, Model Context Protocol, architecture, integration, governance, enterprise systems, model orchestration, compliance, security, scalable, vendor selection, SaaS, multi-model, agent frameworks, cross-functional, lifecycle management
    </keywords-matched>
    <excitement-rating>HIGH</excitement-rating>
  </application>

  <application id="huron-digital-senior-director-applied-ai-growth-lead-2026">
    <company>Huron Consulting</company>
    <role>Digital Senior Director - Applied AI Growth Lead - Education &amp; Research</role>
    <location>Chicago - 550 Van Buren</location>
    <salary-range>$210,000-$275,000 base, $262,500-$371,250 total comp</salary-range>
    <date-applied>2026-02-12</date-applied>
    <status>resume-generated</status>
    <resume-path>resumes/huron-digital-senior-director-applied-ai-growth-lead/resume.md</resume-path>
    <job-url>https://huron.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/huroncareers/userHome</job-url>
    <notes>
      Senior Director-level AI Growth Lead role in global consulting firm. Owns AI GTM strategy, AI product development (ideation to launch), and revenue generation for Education &amp; Research vertical. Strong match: $1.5B pipeline generation at Google Cloud (10X growth, 9 months), AI strategy at McDonald's (350+ use cases, 22 patterns, 10 funded), multi-agent AI product development (Principio), build-vs-buy acquisition SME (Stratozone), 88-contributor matrixed program leadership, C-suite advisory (CIO endorsement, CEO presentations), consulting DNA (Revere Group practice lead, 8 advisory engagements). Key differentiator: rare combination of proven AI GTM revenue generation at scale AND hands-on AI product development. Primary gap: no direct Education &amp; Research vertical experience — mitigated via adjacency evidence (AI-powered course production pipeline, 154-person enterprise learning program integrated into Tech Academy, university mentorship at UIUC). Gap strategy: position AI GTM expertise as primary qualification that makes vertical knowledge secondary and acquirable. Context: Senior/Executive seniority, Executive/Sales hybrid function, Enterprise consulting firm. Travel: 50% acceptable (demonstrated via 20-city global tour, Rotterdam, RSA Conference).
    </notes>
    <keywords-matched>
      AI Go-To-Market (GTM), Generative AI, Large Language Models (LLM), Machine Learning, enterprise-scale transformation, AI product management, consulting, advisory, revenue-generating AI offerings, build vs. buy vs. partner, matrixed organization, digital transformation, executive stakeholder, program management, AI governance, training program design
    </keywords-matched>
    <excitement-rating>HIGH</excitement-rating>
  </application>
</job-applications>
