<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Career Positions - Position-Focused Extraction
  Contains full STAR activities without identity/credentials
  For identity and credentials, reference career-profile.xml
  Last updated: 2026-01-13
-->
<career-positions version="1.0" last-updated="2026-01-15">

  <!-- Cross-reference for identity/credentials -->
  <reference file="career-profile.xml" sections="identity,credentials,keywords"/>

  <!-- POSITIONS with full STAR activities -->
  <positions>

    <!-- MCDONALD'S: Principal AI Architect -->
    <position id="mcd-2024" company="McDonald's Corporation" type="current">
      <title>Principal AI Architect (Generative AI)</title>
      <level>Director-equivalent</level>
      <dates start="2024-03" end="present"/>

      <activity id="mcd-2024-10layer" type="strategic">
        <situation>McDonald's lacked comprehensive enterprise AI architecture to guide technology investments across 40,000+ restaurant locations globally, consumer platforms, and internal business functions.</situation>
        <task>Design target state architecture for enterprise AI platform on Google Cloud Platform covering all layers from user interface to governance.</task>
        <action>Designed 10-layer architecture (Interface, Agent Orchestration, Agent Runtime, Tools/Functions, Models, Knowledge/Data, MLOps/AIOps, Infrastructure, AI Developer Experience, Governance). Defined three-platform model. Made key decisions on A2A protocol, MCP, Kafka, multi-model strategy.</action>
        <result>Designed 10-layer enterprise AI platform architecture endorsed by CIO as McDonald's strategic technical direction; implementation now underway. Created 45+ standardized artifacts.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="enterprise-architecture"><skill>Target state architecture</skill><technology>TOGAF</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="ai-ml"><skill>AI platform architecture</skill><technology>A2A Protocol</technology><technology>MCP</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="cloud-platforms"><technology>Google Cloud Platform</technology></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="mcd-2024-usecases" type="strategic">
        <situation>McDonald's business strategy team developing enterprise AI strategy but lacked comprehensive view of AI opportunities across 8 global business functions.</situation>
        <task>Co-lead AI opportunity discovery workshops and identify reusable architecture patterns.</task>
        <action>Co-led AI opportunity discovery across 8 business functions through 16 workshops (2 per function) as core team member. Researched and authored 10 AI megatrend papers. Synthesized workshop findings to identify common patterns.</action>
        <result>Co-led discovery through 16 workshops; synthesized 325 use cases into 22 reusable architectural patterns, 10 of which are now submitted for funding. Delivered 10 megatrend papers.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="ai-ml"><skill>Use case analysis</skill><technology>Gemini</technology><technology>Claude</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="enterprise-architecture"><skill>Value stream mapping</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="mcd-2024-agents" type="technical">
        <technical-calibration>
          <tools>Copilot Studio (low-code), Power Automate (low-code), Rovo (low-code)</tools>
          <scope>Practical automation for architecture team, decision support for leadership</scope>
          <not>Distributed systems engineering, production-scale agent deployment, custom code development</not>
          <positioning>Applied AI for business value, not deep technical engineering. Demonstrates ability to deliver quick wins with appropriate tools.</positioning>
        </technical-calibration>
        <situation>Senior leadership needed tools to evaluate AI investment business cases; architecture team needed automated research capabilities.</situation>
        <task>Develop AI-powered decision support and automation tools for senior leadership and architecture team.</task>
        <action>Built decision support tool (Decision Advisor) used by senior leadership (VP through CIO) to interrogate central initiative tracking repository. Developed 3 additional agents using Copilot Studio and Power Automate: GenAI Architecture Assistant, Current State Researcher, Business Architecture Modeler. Currently building Global Program Management Agent.</action>
        <result>Built decision support tool used by senior leadership (VP through CIO) to evaluate AI investment business cases. Deployed 3 additional agents supporting architecture team. Fifth agent in development.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="ai-ml"><skill>Multi-agent systems</skill><skill>RAG pipelines</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="mcd-2024-opmodel" type="strategic">
        <situation>Following reorganization, architecture function lacked standardized operating model across Solution, Business, Enterprise, Data, and AI domains.</situation>
        <task>Establish comprehensive architecture operating model to standardize practices.</task>
        <action>Applied Six Sigma SIPOC, SCAMPI/A, BIZBOK, TOGAF. Defined 9 core services, 45 artifacts, 12 services, 14 roles. Mapped 40 value streams.</action>
        <result>Established operating model covering 5 domains. Created 9 core services, 45 artifacts, 14 role definitions. Mapped 40 value streams.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="enterprise-architecture"><skill>Architecture operating model</skill><technology>TOGAF</technology><technology>BIZBOK</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="six-sigma"><skill>Process improvement</skill></domain>
        </tags>
        <permanence status="active" years="0+">Adopted as McDonald's architecture standard</permanence>
      </activity>

      <activity id="mcd-2024-amazon" type="strategic">
        <situation>McDonald's pursued strategic loyalty partnership with Amazon requiring secure account linking between platforms.</situation>
        <task>Develop enterprise architecture strategy for Amazon loyalty partnership including account linking and integration patterns.</task>
        <action>Developed EA strategy. Built value streams. Conducted capability analysis. Co-designed WebView account linking. Created architecture diagrams and sequence diagrams. Defined earn/burn patterns.</action>
        <result>Delivered EA strategy for Amazon partnership. Created secure WebView account linking architecture. Established earn/burn integration patterns.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="martech-loyalty"><skill>Loyalty program architecture</skill><skill>Account linking</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="enterprise-architecture"><skill>Capability modeling</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="mcd-2024-gcpchamps" type="leadership">
        <situation>McDonald's migrating to GCP but workforce lacked cloud skills. Need for structured training program.</situation>
        <task>Design and lead cloud training program to accelerate GCP adoption.</task>
        <action>Designed and led comprehensive GCP Champs training program. Coordinated certification paths. Led implementation and tracked metrics.</action>
        <result>Designed and led GCP Champs: 154 participants, 100 certifications, 7X completion rate vs. baseline. 166 pull-through employees (2X effect). Program praised by CIO; being integrated into Global IT Tech Academy.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="program-management"><skill>Training program design</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="cloud-platforms"><technology>Google Cloud Platform</technology></domain>
        </tags>
        <permanence status="active" years="0+">Being integrated into Global IT Tech Academy</permanence>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- PRINCIPIO GROUP (Current) -->
    <position id="principio-2023" company="Principio Group" type="concurrent">
      <title>Founder &amp; Principal</title>
      <dates start="2023-04" end="present"/>

      <activity id="principio-2023-waivepath" type="technical">
        <situation>Sales professionals lacked resources to learn prompt engineering and apply AI to sales best practices.</situation>
        <task>Lead product development and engineering for sales enablement platform.</task>
        <action>Architected full-stack platform (React/Next.js, Firebase, Cloud Run, Stripe). Built 8-agent content production system with Claude and Gemini. Created 50+ articles, podcasts, prompts.</action>
        <result>Built and shipped AI-powered sales enablement platform: 8-agent content production system, React/Next.js frontend, Firebase backend, Stripe payments. Limited commercial traction revealed GTM gaps—built for salespeople who don't buy learning products. Applying lessons to Agentient.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="software-development"><technology>React</technology><technology>Next.js</technology><technology>Firebase</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="ai-ml"><skill>Multi-agent systems</skill><technology>Claude</technology><technology>Gemini</technology></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="principio-2024-agentient" type="strategic">
        <technical-depth-note>
          Most sophisticated technical work in current portfolio. Custom MCP servers (Python), multi-agent orchestration, RAG pipeline, cross-platform context management. Contrasts with McDonald's low-code work—demonstrates range from lightweight automation (Copilot Studio) to custom system architecture (Python, MCP, Firebase). This is the primary evidence for "builder-architect hybrid" claim when technical depth is questioned.
        </technical-depth-note>
        <situation>Startup founders lack AI tools providing compounding intelligence throughout product development lifecycle.</situation>
        <task>Design AI-first B2B SaaS platform providing AI co-pilot capabilities for startups.</task>
        <action>Designed 7-module suite. Personally building stack: Python, Cloud Run, Firebase, MCP for tool integration, RAG pipeline. Implemented custom MCP servers connecting Claude to Notion and filesystem. Developed multi-agent orchestration system. Applied MVP approach from WaivePath learnings.</action>
        <result>Building AI co-founder platform with multi-agent orchestration, MCP server integration, and cross-platform context management. Flow module in early beta, acquiring users. Technical work informs enterprise AI architecture consulting. 100% ownership.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="ai-ml"><skill>AI platform architecture</skill><technology>Agent Development Kit</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="software-development"><technology>React</technology><technology>Firebase</technology></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- GOOGLE CLOUD: Principal Program Manager -->
    <position id="google-2021" company="Google Cloud" type="previous">
      <title>Principal Program Manager</title>
      <dates start="2019-12" end="2023-03"/>
      <departure-context>Laid off in 2023 reduction; had back-to-back Exceeds Expectations ratings in prior two performance cycles. Team was deprioritized, not performance.</departure-context>

      <activity id="google-2021-iba-program" type="leadership">
        <situation>Sales teams lacked industry knowledge to engage business executives. No unified methodology across siloed enablement teams.</situation>
        <task>Build largest cross-functional program of career developing industry business architecture content.</task>
        <action>Managed 88 contributors, 10 workstreams, 3 cross-functional teams, 12 industries. Engaged Accenture for initial 6-industry bill-of-materials. Created internal website. Recruited volunteers. Partnered with Distinguished Engineer. Added McKinsey research. Launched 20% project for TPMs.</action>
        <result>Delivered content for 12 industries with 6 use cases. Led 88 contributors across 10 workstreams without direct authority. Doubled traffic to enablement content. Became basis for Level 300 accreditation standard (still in use).</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="program-management"><skill>Cross-functional leadership</skill><skill>Volunteer coordination</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="enterprise-architecture"><skill>Capability modeling</skill></domain>
        </tags>
        <permanence status="active" years="3+">Became Level 300 accreditation standard—still in use</permanence>
      </activity>

      <activity id="google-2020-ai-content" type="technical">
        <situation>SME resources scarce, content stale. Course production took 6-8 weeks. JWCC contract required 11 courses in 2 months.</situation>
        <task>Develop innovative content production pipeline to address SME scarcity.</task>
        <action>Developed AI pipeline: speech-to-text transcription, LLM synthesis, manual editing, text-to-speech voiceover, audio remastering, video production, LMS deployment.</action>
        <result>Reduced production from 6-8 weeks to less than 1 week (85%). Reduced SME time 90%. Delivered 11 JWCC courses in 2 months. Led public sector enablement.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="ai-ml"><skill>Prompt engineering</skill><technology>ChatGPT</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="sales-enablement"><skill>Course design</skill><technology>WaveNet</technology></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="google-2019-competitive" type="technical">
        <situation>Sales teams needed competitive positioning against Azure and AWS. Leadership needed analysis for executive communications.</situation>
        <task>Research and document competitive insights. Train on competitive positioning.</task>
        <action>Authored AWS re:Invent 2019 synopsis. Prepared Goldman Sachs response for CEO. Created Azure training for global conference. Mentored UIUC students on AI competitive analysis.</action>
        <result>Delivered AWS analysis to global force. Contributed to CEO communications. Trained 500+ with 4.6 rating. Mentored university AI project.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="competitive-intelligence"><skill>Competitive analysis</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="technology-evangelism"><skill>Public speaking</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- GOOGLE CLOUD: Head of Value Engineering -->
    <position id="google-2018" company="Google Cloud" type="previous">
      <title>Head of Value Engineering</title>
      <dates start="2018-01" end="2019-11"/>

      <activity id="google-2018-pipeline" type="strategic">
        <situation>Value Engineering nascent (~18 months), $150M assessed business. Fragmented initiatives (Stratozone, CloudPhysics, Velostrata) without unified strategy.</situation>
        <task>Develop and scale global value engineering strategy. Consolidate fragmented initiatives.</task>
        <action>Built Global Assessment and Planning Program consolidating Stratozone, CloudPhysics, Velostrata. Renegotiated Stratozone contract for free capabilities. Reinvested savings into 20-city global training tour. Trained ~1/3 of global sales force.</action>
        <result>Generated $1.5B pipeline in 9 months (10X from $150M). Improved forecast accuracy 60%. Reduced sales cycle 70%. Increased VM migration win rate 5%.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="value-engineering"><skill>TCO analysis</skill><skill>Contract negotiation</skill><technology>Stratozone</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="program-management"><skill>Global program execution</skill></domain>
        </tags>
        <permanence status="adopted" years="6+">Program structure adopted globally</permanence>
      </activity>

      <activity id="google-2018-stratozone" type="strategic">
        <situation>Google Cloud Engineering preferred acquisition over internal development for discovery/assessment capabilities. GPM for Compute wanted tooling to support migrations.</situation>
        <task>Serve as subject matter expert for acquisition evaluation; provide recommendation on which company to acquire.</task>
        <action>Served as SME for Stratozone acquisition evaluation. Conducted build-vs-buy analysis and technical due diligence. Evaluated competing vendors and provided recommendation that informed acquisition decision—if recommendation had been negative, acquisition would not have proceeded. Participated in vendor negotiations. Maintained CEO relationship facilitating deal.</action>
        <result>Served as SME for Google Cloud's Stratozone acquisition (closed 2020); provided recommendation that informed acquisition decision. Product became Google Cloud Migration Center—still in production today.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="value-engineering"><technology>Stratozone</technology><technology>Google Cloud Migration Center</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>Deal negotiation</skill></domain>
        </tags>
        <permanence status="production" years="7+">Became Google Cloud Migration Center—still in production</permanence>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- GOOGLE CLOUD: Principal Strategic Advisor -->
    <position id="google-2016" company="Google Cloud" type="previous">
      <title>Principal Strategic Advisor</title>
      <dates start="2016-03" end="2017-12"/>

      <activity id="google-2016-security" type="leadership">
        <situation>Google Cloud nascent, establishing enterprise credibility against Microsoft and AWS. Security and compliance blocking adoption.</situation>
        <task>Support sales with C-level technical presentations. Develop enterprise security messaging.</task>
        <action>Became de-facto security SME creating reusable messaging. Co-developed global customer engineer workshop establishing first security specialist team. Presented at RSA, Advisen. Supported PayPal, Capital One, HSBC, Target, Best Buy, Kohl's.</action>
        <result>Established enterprise security credibility. Created first security specialist team. Developed reusable messaging. Earned GCP Architect certification. Published Fast Magazine article.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="technology-evangelism"><skill>Executive presentations</skill><skill>Public speaking</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="cloud-platforms"><skill>Cloud security</skill><technology>Google Cloud Platform</technology></domain>
        </tags>
        <permanence status="active" years="8+">Security Specialist role became part of Customer Engineer career ladder</permanence>
      </activity>

      <activity id="google-2016-highland" type="technical">
        <situation>Highland Technologies consuming ~120,000 cores for algorithmic trading. Failures appearing. Cloud Front-end Service flooded affecting Highland and SnapChat.</situation>
        <task>Investigate root cause of infrastructure constraints affecting two key customers.</task>
        <action>Gained access to internal tools via SREs. Discovered CFE flooding. Met client to determine root cause: small job sizes creating massive I/O. Collaborated with client to redistribute workloads while waiting for hardware.</action>
        <result>Identified root cause (job design pattern). Developed workload redistribution. Unexpected win: new distributed design proved better than original and was retained.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="cloud-platforms"><skill>Cloud architecture</skill><technology>Google Cloud Platform</technology></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- MICROSOFT: Senior Business Development Manager -->
    <position id="microsoft-2012" company="Microsoft Corporation" type="previous">
      <title>Senior Business Development Manager</title>
      <dates start="2012" end="2014-11"/>

      <activity id="microsoft-2013-investment" type="strategic">
        <situation>Microsoft investing heavily for marquee Windows Store apps. Product groups had priority lists and investment budgets.</situation>
        <task>Secure strategic partnership deals through internal investment and cross-team collaboration.</task>
        <action>Built business cases for internal investment. Structured multi-technology deals (Windows Phone, Windows 8, Xbox, Azure, Advertising). Applied "One Microsoft" approach across teams.</action>
        <result>Raised $2.5M internal investment (2013-2014). Recognized as "whale hunter" for largest brands. Developed Corporate VP relationships.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>Partnership structuring</skill><skill>Deal negotiation</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="microsoft-2013-walmart" type="strategic">
        <situation>Predecessor unable to secure Walmart partnership in 3+ years. Walmart relationship strained after Windows 8 holiday disappointment.</situation>
        <task>Break through to secure Walmart platform partnership.</task>
        <action>Targeted VUDU as beachhead (Xbox app). Started Azure discussion. Applied "One Microsoft" coordinating Retail, Advertising, Xbox teams. Organized HQ meeting with Chief Merchandising Officer. Proposed pre-installed Walmart app. Secured $500K funding.</action>
        <result>Secured broader partnership (Xbox/VUDU, advertising, retail strategy). Delivered apps. Walmart leadership called out workstream as partnership highlight.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>C-level engagement</skill><skill>Consultative selling</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="microsoft-2012-scripps" type="strategic">
        <situation>Scripps Networks (HGTV, Food Network) valuable brands for Windows 8 launch. Few months to deadline with insufficient resources.</situation>
        <task>Secure Scripps brands for Windows platforms.</task>
        <action>Secured executive briefing. Met COO then CEO at CES. Secured CEO support for Food Network app. Personally coded significant portions of Windows 8 app in C# using WinRT APIs—learned platform while delivering under deadline.</action>
        <result>Food Network became one of 5 major showcase apps for Windows 8 launch. Demonstrated business development plus technical delivery.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>C-level engagement</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="software-development"><technology>C#</technology></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- MICROSOFT: Senior Platform Strategy Advisor -->
    <position id="microsoft-2008" company="Microsoft Corporation" type="previous">
      <title>Senior Platform Strategy Advisor</title>
      <dates start="2008-02" end="2012"/>

      <activity id="microsoft-2009-aon" type="strategic">
        <situation>AON CTO invited Microsoft and Google to present on cloud. Microsoft transitioning with "Software + Services" strategy and BPOS.</situation>
        <task>Win competitive engagement against Google.</task>
        <action>Developed and presented Microsoft cloud migration strategy emphasizing gradual migration while protecting security, confidentiality, compliance. Positioned against Google's enterprise gaps.</action>
        <result>Won against Google. AON became first major Central Region BPOS customer. Invited to Rotterdam CTO conference. Asked to train other teams on winning against Google.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="cloud-platforms"><skill>Cloud security</skill><technology>Microsoft Azure</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="technology-evangelism"><skill>Competitive positioning</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="microsoft-2011-tribune-tablet" type="strategic">
        <situation>Tribune board asking about digital mobile strategy after iPad launch. Windows had less than 1% share requiring compelling case.</situation>
        <task>Develop comprehensive mobile strategy for Tribune to position Windows as strategic platform.</task>
        <action>Conducted deep industry research (advertising, distribution). Built prototype. Developed vision encompassing all Tribune properties. Presented to CEO within one week of Steve Gable intro.</action>
        <result>Identified $3.3B tablet partnership opportunity through self-initiated market analysis; secured CEO presentation within weeks. Windows tablet deal lost to platform issues outside control, but converted relationship into Azure partnership with $1.5M annual savings. Recognition: Gold Club, 3x Top Contributor, MGX Best in Class.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>C-level engagement</skill><skill>Consultative selling</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="technology-evangelism"><skill>Thought leadership</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="microsoft-2010-tribune-azure" type="strategic">
        <situation>Tribune contract renewal struggling. EVP Steve Gable had "Content Cloud" initiative to centralize content and reduce data centers.</situation>
        <task>Strengthen Tribune partnership by identifying strategic technology opportunities.</task>
        <action>Hosted Silverlight workshop. Findings forwarded to EVP. Learned about Content Cloud. Received permission for confidential "Red Dog" (Azure) disclosure. Secured pilot.</action>
        <result>Secured major Azure deal with significant PR. Delivered $1.5M annual operational cost reduction through content centralization.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="cloud-platforms"><skill>Migration strategy</skill><technology>Microsoft Azure</technology></domain>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>Executive relationship building</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- MICROSOFT: Architect Evangelist -->
    <position id="microsoft-2006" company="Microsoft Corporation" type="previous">
      <title>Architect Evangelist</title>
      <dates start="2006-04" end="2008-02"/>

      <activity id="microsoft-2007-office" type="tactical">
        <situation>Office 2007 and Windows Vista launching. Major commodities exchange seeking to modernize investment modeling.</situation>
        <task>Promote and drive adoption of new technologies through enterprise engagements.</task>
        <action>Integrated investment modeling into Office for commodities exchange as launch showcase. Executed multi-million dollar Office business application deal.</action>
        <result>Delivered Office 2007 launch showcase. Executed multi-million dollar deal. Circle of Excellence 2008 (team award).</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="technology-evangelism"><skill>Technical storytelling</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- ALLSTATE -->
    <position id="allstate-2004" company="Allstate Financial" type="previous">
      <title>Enterprise Architect</title>
      <dates start="2004-01" end="2006-03"/>

      <activity id="allstate-2005-consolidation" type="strategic">
        <situation>Three core back-office life systems needed consolidation. New system had critical performance problems. Engineer lacked experience. IBM support not resolving.</situation>
        <task>Lead consolidation program. Resolve critical performance issue.</task>
        <action>Led team of architects. When crisis emerged, escalated to VP then IBM management. IBM identified retired Colorado expert. Hired as contractor.</action>
        <result>Within two weeks, issue diagnosed and resolved. Project back on track. Successfully consolidated three systems into one.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="enterprise-architecture"><skill>Architecture governance</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="program-management"><skill>Stakeholder management</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="allstate-2005-sixsigma-policy" type="strategic">
        <situation>Policy processing SLA 28 days, actual 35 days. Higher rejection rates. SLA ranges allowed departments to operate at upper bounds while individual scorecards showed green.</situation>
        <task>Complete COO-sponsored Six Sigma project reducing policy cycle time.</task>
        <action>Analyzed cycle time data. Conducted value stream analysis. Identified root cause (SLA ranges). Presented to COO. Identified low-hanging fruit. Implemented control plan.</action>
        <result>Reduced cycle time from 35 to 28 days (20% improvement). Improved acceptance rate 14%. Earned Six Sigma Black Belt.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="six-sigma"><skill>Process improvement</skill><skill>Root cause analysis</skill><skill>Control plans</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>C-level engagement</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- REVERE GROUP -->
    <position id="revere-2000" company="The Revere Group" type="previous">
      <title>Managing Consultant / Practice Lead</title>
      <dates start="2000-09" end="2003-12"/>

      <activity id="revere-2001-manpower" type="technical">
        <situation>Leading front-end team for complex B2B Manpower application. Team member's code causing performance problems.</situation>
        <task>Lead team and resolve critical performance issue.</task>
        <action>Developed prototype demonstrating improvement. Raised impasse. Project manager approved. Rewrote code.</action>
        <result>5X performance improvement. Reduced code from 3,000 to 100 lines (97%). Successfully delivered application.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="software-development"><skill>Code optimization</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="revere-2002-practice" type="leadership">
        <situation>After Manpower success, opportunity to lead Microsoft Technologies practice during dot-com aftermath.</situation>
        <task>Lead practice managing consultants and driving business development.</task>
        <action>Managed 10 consultants. Led pre-sales. Developed service strategy. Won $1M AVSC deal.</action>
        <result>Led 10-person team. ~50% win rate. Closed $1M deal. Left when offshore competition shifted market to cost focus.</result>
        <tags>
          <domain ref="business-development"><skill>Pre-sales</skill></domain>
          <domain ref="program-management"><skill>Cross-functional leadership</skill></domain>
        </tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- IBS -->
    <position id="ibs-1999" company="Interactive Business Systems" type="previous">
      <title>Managing Consultant</title>
      <dates start="1999-02" end="2000-09"/>

      <activity id="ibs-1999-crm" type="technical">
        <situation>Strong Funds legacy CRM had Y2K issues and lacked features.</situation>
        <task>Lead development of new CRM application.</task>
        <action>Led team. Captured requirements. Architected in VB.NET. Designed UI. Developed subsystems.</action>
        <result>Delivered CRM with improved performance and Y2K compliance.</result>
        <tags><domain ref="software-development"><technology>Visual Basic .NET</technology></domain></tags>
      </activity>

      <activity id="ibs-1999-identity" type="technical">
        <situation>No central credential management. Help desk overload. Security risk from orphaned credentials.</situation>
        <task>Develop centralized identity management system.</task>
        <action>Gathered requirements. Studied APIs. Developed identity management code.</action>
        <result>Delivered system managing Windows, Novell, Unix, and internal app credentials.</result>
        <tags><domain ref="software-development"><technology>Visual Basic .NET</technology></domain></tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- PQ AFRICA -->
    <position id="pq-africa-1995" company="PQ Africa" type="previous">
      <title>Managing Consultant</title>
      <dates start="1995-09" end="1999-01"/>

      <activity id="pq-1996-automation" type="technical">
        <situation>Infrastructure deployments at Metropolitan Life and Engen Petroleum involved thousands of PCs with time-consuming manual process.</situation>
        <task>Automate software deployment to improve efficiency.</task>
        <action>Developed scripting languages for automated PC deployment.</action>
        <result>5X faster deployment (20 machines/person/day). Became company differentiator. Earned MCSE.</result>
        <tags><domain ref="software-development"><skill>Application architecture</skill></domain></tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

    <!-- SHOPRITE -->
    <position id="shoprite-1989" company="Shoprite" type="previous">
      <title>Trainee / System Software Programmer</title>
      <dates start="1989-08" end="1995-09"/>

      <activity id="shoprite-1991-drivers" type="technical">
        <situation>Company adopting PCs as part of distributed computing strategy. Needed programmers for driver development.</situation>
        <task>Develop and maintain drivers for mid-range to mainframe communication.</task>
        <action>Invested in personal PC. Completed COBOL training and certification. Developed printer and scanner drivers. Completed Computer Science diploma.</action>
        <result>Delivered printer and scanner drivers. Earned COBOL cert and CS diploma. Foundation for PC ecosystem transition.</result>
        <tags><domain ref="software-development"><skill>Application architecture</skill></domain></tags>
      </activity>
    </position>

  </positions>

</career-positions>
