<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Interview Positioning Guide v1.0
  Derived from career coaching session: 2026-01-13
  Purpose: Talking points, Q&A guidance, vulnerability handling
  
  Key Insight: Robin's differentiator is BUILDER-ARCHITECT HYBRID
  Most Principal Architects either think strategically OR write code.
  Robin does both. Lead with this.
-->
<interview-positioning version="1.0" last-updated="2026-01-13">

  <!-- CORE NARRATIVE -->
  <narrative>
    <elevator-pitch>
      I'm a builder-architect hybrid. Most Principal Architects either think strategically 
      or write code—I do both. I've stood up five new functions at Google and Microsoft, 
      including the program that led to Google Cloud Migration Center. I designed McDonald's 
      enterprise AI architecture AND built agents that are running in production. I can see 
      the big picture and I can ship.
    </elevator-pitch>
    
    <differentiators>
      <differentiator id="builder-architect">
        <claim>Builder-Architect Hybrid</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>4 McDonald's agents deployed (GCP Champs automation, TPM project analysis, capability modeling, architecture research)</proof>
          <proof>WaivePath 8-agent orchestration system built from scratch</proof>
          <proof>Food Network Windows 8 app (85-95% of production code)</proof>
          <proof>Agentient multi-agent system with MCP server integration</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I can architect solutions I actually know how to build. My hands-on agent 
          development at Agentient directly informs my enterprise architecture work 
          at McDonald's."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>
      
      <differentiator id="zero-to-one">
        <claim>Zero-to-One Program Builder</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>Value Engineering: $150M → $1.5B pipeline (10X growth)</proof>
          <proof>Industry Business Architecture: 88 contributors, 12 industries</proof>
          <proof>GCP Champs: 154 direct + 166 pull-through participants, 7X completion rate</proof>
          <proof>Stratozone program → acquired → Google Cloud Migration Center</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I deliberately pursue emerging functions where I can build from zero. 
          The trade-off is organizational volatility—these functions get restructured. 
          The benefit is I've stood up five new practices, each time creating infrastructure 
          that outlasted my tenure."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>
      
      <differentiator id="executive-access">
        <claim>Rapid Executive Engagement</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>Tribune: Workshop attendee → CEO presentation in weeks</proof>
          <proof>AON: Competitive win against Google, invited to Rotterdam CTO conference</proof>
          <proof>McDonald's CIO adoption of architecture, VP adoption of Agent Maria</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I research clients' strategic initiatives deeply before engaging. 
          This consultative approach opens doors that pure sales can't reach."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>
      
      <differentiator id="ma-involvement">
        <claim>M&amp;A Strategic Contribution</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>Served as SME on Stratozone acquisition team</proof>
          <proof>Conducted build vs. buy analysis for GPM Compute</proof>
          <proof>Identified product gaps, negotiated vendor roadmap commitments</proof>
          <proof>Connected M&amp;A team with target CEO</proof>
          <proof>Product became Google Cloud Migration Center</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I drove the acquisition recommendation that became Google Cloud Migration Center—
          consolidated competing partner programs, conducted build vs. buy analysis, 
          negotiated vendor commitments, and connected M&amp;A with the CEO."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>
    </differentiators>
  </narrative>

  <!-- COMMON INTERVIEW QUESTIONS -->
  <common-questions>
    
    <question id="mcdonalds-tenure">
      <prompt>You've been at McDonald's less than a year. What have you actually delivered?</prompt>
      <concern>Short tenure with potentially thin concrete achievements</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        McDonald's engaged me to design their AI platform architecture, which I delivered 
        and the CIO adopted. But I also built working agents—the GCP Champs automation 
        serving 150+ participants, the TPM project analysis tool that our VP uses, and 
        architecture research tooling for the EA team. I believe architects should prove 
        their designs work by building pieces of them.
      </recommended-response>
      <proof-points>
        <proof>10-layer architecture adopted as technical roadmap</proof>
        <proof>4 AI agents deployed and in active use</proof>
        <proof>GCP Champs: 100 certifications, 7X completion rate</proof>
        <proof>325 use cases synthesized into 22 reusable patterns</proof>
      </proof-points>
    </question>
    
    <question id="google-departures">
      <prompt>You had multiple role changes at Google. What happened?</prompt>
      <concern>Pattern of restructuring rather than advancement</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I deliberately pursue zero-to-one opportunities—building new functions in emerging 
        spaces. The trade-off is organizational volatility. Field CTO got centralized to 
        engineering because Google wanted VPs with 20+ years of industry experience. 
        Value Engineering I scaled 10X, then they brought in specialists with 25 years 
        of specific experience to take it further. Industry Enablement was deprioritized 
        in a strategic shift. But the Stratozone program I built became Google Cloud 
        Migration Center. I build things that last even when my role doesn't.
      </recommended-response>
      <reframe>
        "Restructured out" → "Built something valuable enough that it needed its own organization"
      </reframe>
    </question>
    
    <question id="technical-depth">
      <prompt>Are you actually technical, or just a strategist who makes decks?</prompt>
      <concern>Principal Architect title often means paper architecture only</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I wrote 85% of the production code for the Food Network Windows 8 app—that was 
        a flagship launch showcase, C# on a new platform with limited documentation and 
        a hard deadline. At Agentient, I'm building multi-agent systems with MCP integration 
        and cross-platform context management. At McDonald's, I use Copilot Studio and 
        Power Automate for practical automation. I operate at whatever technical level 
        solves the problem.
      </recommended-response>
      <calibration-note>
        McDonald's agents are low-code (Copilot Studio, Power Automate, Rovo). 
        Don't conflate with distributed systems engineering. 
        Agentient work is more sophisticated (MCP server, multi-agent orchestration).
      </calibration-note>
    </question>
    
    <question id="pipeline-number">
      <prompt>You claim $1.5B pipeline. How do you attribute that to yourself?</prompt>
      <concern>Large numbers at big companies often reflect proximity, not causation</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        When I took over Value Engineering, my predecessor had built a partnership with 
        Stratozone running at about $150M pipeline. I made the decision to scale it globally—
        flew to 20 cities to train the sales force, renegotiated the partner contract to 
        add capabilities at no cost, and reinvested savings into the enablement program. 
        I also consolidated a second partner (CloudPhysics) under the same umbrella. 
        In 9 months, the program scaled to $1.5B. The causal chain is clear: I built the 
        infrastructure that enabled the field to qualify and quantify deals at scale.
      </recommended-response>
      <better-framing>
        "Scaled Google Cloud's value engineering program from $150M to $1.5B pipeline (10X growth) 
        by training the global sales force across 20 cities, renegotiating partner contracts, 
        and standardizing TCO methodology."
      </better-framing>
    </question>
    
    <question id="tribune-opportunity">
      <prompt>You mention a $3.3B opportunity that didn't close. How is that an achievement?</prompt>
      <concern>Claiming credit for deals that didn't happen</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        The $3.3B demonstrates capability, not outcome. My job was business development—
        identify opportunities, secure executive access, build strategic cases. I went from 
        a technical workshop to CEO presentation within weeks through self-initiated market 
        research. The tablet deal didn't close due to device quality issues outside my control. 
        What I did convert was a major Windows Azure partnership that saved Tribune $1.5M 
        annually. The Azure deal was the actual win; the tablet opportunity shows how I find 
        and pursue strategic possibilities.
      </recommended-response>
      <better-framing>
        "Identified $3.3B tablet partnership opportunity through self-initiated market analysis; 
        secured CEO presentation within weeks. Converted relationship into Windows Azure 
        partnership with $1.5M annual cost savings."
      </better-framing>
    </question>
    
    <question id="venture-experience">
      <prompt>Your startup ventures don't seem successful. Why should I value that experience?</prompt>
      <concern>Founder titles without market success</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        WaivePath taught me that target market selection matters more than product quality—
        we built for salespeople who don't buy learning products instead of sales enablement 
        professionals who do. That's a $50K lesson I won't repeat. The technical work was 
        real: I designed an 8-agent content orchestration system from scratch, built the 
        entire platform, and shipped to market. Agentient applies those lessons—extensive 
        market validation, founder interviews, and I own 100% so partner dynamics can't 
        derail execution. The hands-on development keeps my technical skills sharp, which 
        makes me a better enterprise architect.
      </recommended-response>
      <reframe>
        "Failed startup" → "Shipped product, learned market validation lessons I'm applying now"
      </reframe>
    </question>
    
    <question id="325-use-cases">
      <prompt>What does "analyzed 325 use cases" actually mean?</prompt>
      <concern>Large numbers might be superficial taxonomy work</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        We ran discovery workshops across 8 business functions to identify AI opportunities. 
        I took 325 raw ideas, consolidated duplicates, wrote problem statements and solution 
        alternatives for each, then analyzed the full portfolio to identify 22 reusable 
        architectural patterns. It's portfolio synthesis and pattern extraction—not deep 
        technical design on 325 individual solutions. The value is helping McDonald's 
        prioritize where limited AI engineering resources should focus for maximum impact.
      </recommended-response>
      <better-framing>
        "Led AI opportunity discovery across 8 business functions, synthesizing 325 use cases 
        into 22 reusable architectural patterns; developing prioritization framework to 
        maximize engineering team impact."
      </better-framing>
    </question>
    
    <question id="88-contributors">
      <prompt>You say you "managed" 88 people. Did you actually manage them?</prompt>
      <concern>Overclaiming authority</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        Let me be precise: I led a cross-functional program with 88 contributors across 
        10 workstreams through Google's 20% project framework. I recruited, coordinated, 
        and provided performance feedback, but I had no hire/fire authority or budget. 
        The achievement was achieving results through influence rather than positional power—
        which is often harder than direct management.
      </recommended-response>
      <correction>
        Always say "led" not "managed" for this program.
      </correction>
    </question>

  </common-questions>

  <!-- VULNERABILITY HANDLING -->
  <vulnerabilities>
    
    <vulnerability id="role-volatility">
      <concern>Pattern of roles ending via restructure rather than advancement</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        True. Zero-to-one roles in emerging functions are inherently volatile. 
        This is a deliberate trade-off, not a failure pattern.
      </honest-assessment>
      <reframe>
        "I build things that outlast my tenure. The Stratozone program became 
        Google Cloud Migration Center. The enablement standards I created were 
        adopted across Google Cloud GTM. The architecture operating model at 
        McDonald's will guide the organization for years."
      </reframe>
      <proof-of-lasting-impact>
        <proof>Stratozone → Google Cloud Migration Center (permanent product)</proof>
        <proof>Industry BA program → Principal Architect Level 300 accreditation</proof>
        <proof>Enablement standards → adopted across GTM</proof>
      </proof-of-lasting-impact>
    </vulnerability>
    
    <vulnerability id="mcdonalds-paper-architecture">
      <concern>10-layer architecture is not implemented; tenure too short for production deployment</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        True. Target-state architecture has 2-3 year horizon. 
        Less than 1 year tenure means limited production deployment.
      </honest-assessment>
      <mitigation>
        Lead with the 4 agents that ARE running. Frame architecture as "validated by working prototypes."
      </mitigation>
      <talking-point>
        "The architecture is a 2-3 year roadmap. What's running today are the agents 
        I built to prove key patterns work—GCP Champs automation, TPM project analysis, 
        architecture research tools."
      </talking-point>
    </vulnerability>
    
    <vulnerability id="technical-depth-calibration">
      <concern>McDonald's agents are low-code (Copilot Studio), not sophisticated engineering</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        True. Copilot Studio and Power Automate are citizen developer tools. 
        Don't conflate with building distributed systems.
      </honest-assessment>
      <calibration>
        Technical depth ranges from:
        - Production code (Food Network app, C#)
        - Sophisticated system architecture (Agentient, MCP, multi-agent)
        - Practical low-code automation (McDonald's agents)
        Position as "operating at whatever level solves the problem."
      </calibration>
    </vulnerability>
    
    <vulnerability id="venture-traction">
      <concern>Founder titles without commercial success</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        WaivePath has limited traction. Agentient hasn't launched. 
        This is honest. Don't overclaim.
      </honest-assessment>
      <reframe>
        "Founder who shipped product, learned hard lessons about market validation 
        and partner selection, applying those lessons to current work."
      </reframe>
    </vulnerability>

  </vulnerabilities>

  <!-- NUMBERS THAT SURVIVE SCRUTINY -->
  <quantification-guide>
    
    <metric id="pipeline-1.5b" defensibility="high">
      <claim>$1.5B pipeline in 9 months</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        Inherited $150M run-rate → scaled globally via training (20 cities) + 
        partner consolidation + contract renegotiation → 10X growth
      </causal-chain>
      <better-framing>
        "Scaled from $150M to $1.5B" (shows baseline and growth)
      </better-framing>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="stratozone-acquisition" defensibility="high">
      <claim>Drove acquisition recommendation that became Google Cloud Migration Center</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        SME on evaluation team → build vs. buy analysis → gap identification → 
        vendor negotiation → CEO connection → acquisition closed
      </causal-chain>
      <note>This is undersold. Should be headline of Google section.</note>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="tribune-3.3b" defensibility="medium">
      <claim>$3.3B opportunity identified</claim>
      <issue>Deal didn't close. Opportunity identification ≠ achievement.</issue>
      <reframe>
        Lead with capability (CEO access in weeks) and actual win (Azure deal, $1.5M savings).
        Use $3.3B to demonstrate strategic thinking scope, not as outcome.
      </reframe>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="use-cases-325" defensibility="medium">
      <claim>325 AI use cases analyzed</claim>
      <issue>"Analyzed" is ambiguous. Could mean taxonomy or deep design.</issue>
      <clarification>
        Portfolio synthesis + pattern extraction (22 patterns), not 325 individual technical designs.
      </clarification>
      <reframe>
        "Synthesized 325 use cases into 22 reusable architectural patterns"
      </reframe>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="contributors-88" defensibility="high">
      <claim>88 contributors across 10 workstreams</claim>
      <issue>Were not direct reports. Volunteer 20% project.</issue>
      <correction>
        Say "led" not "managed." The achievement is influence without authority.
      </correction>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="gcp-champs" defensibility="high">
      <claim>154 direct + 166 pull-through, 100 certifications, 7X completion rate</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        Designed program → executed training → measured outcomes from reports
      </causal-chain>
      <note>CIO praised program. This is concrete with real metrics.</note>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="agents-deployed" defensibility="medium">
      <claim>4 AI agents deployed at McDonald's</claim>
      <calibration>
        Real and running, but small scale:
        - GCP Champs: ~90 users
        - TPM/Agent Maria: dozens of executives, dozens of proposals
        - Architecture tools: handful of EA users
      </calibration>
      <reframe>
        "Built working agents that validated architecture patterns" 
        rather than "deployed enterprise AI"
      </reframe>
    </metric>

  </quantification-guide>

  <!-- THINGS TO NEVER SAY -->
  <never-say>
    <item reason="Self-assessment that sounds arrogant">
      "I'm the most knowledgeable person on AI at McDonald's"
    </item>
    <item reason="Reveals misaligned priorities">
      "McDonald's is just my income source; my passion is elsewhere"
    </item>
    <item reason="Conflates low-code with software engineering">
      "I deployed AI agents across McDonald's enterprise" (they're small-scale experiments)
    </item>
    <item reason="Claims outcome that didn't happen">
      "I achieved a $3.3B deal at Microsoft" (opportunity, not win)
    </item>
    <item reason="Overclaims authority">
      "I managed 88 people at Google" (led program, no hire/fire)
    </item>
    <item reason="Paper architecture isn't achievement at Principal level">
      "CIO approved my strategy document" (what's implemented?)
    </item>
  </never-say>

  <!-- POSITIVE REFRAMES -->
  <always-say>
    <item context="When discussing Agentient alongside corporate work">
      "I build AI systems professionally and personally. The hands-on work keeps 
      my technical skills sharp, which makes me a better architect."
    </item>
    <item context="When discussing venture experience">
      "I shipped a product, learned hard lessons about market validation and partner 
      selection, and I'm applying those lessons to my current work."
    </item>
    <item context="When discussing Google role changes">
      "I deliberately pursue zero-to-one opportunities. The Stratozone program I 
      built became Google Cloud Migration Center—I build things that last."
    </item>
    <item context="When asked about technical depth">
      "I operate at whatever technical level solves the problem—from production code 
      to sophisticated agent architectures to practical automation."
    </item>
  </always-say>

</interview-positioning>
