<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Interview Positioning Guide v1.0
  Derived from career coaching session: 2026-01-13
  Purpose: Talking points, Q&A guidance, vulnerability handling
  
  Key Insight: Robin's differentiator is BUILDER-ARCHITECT HYBRID
  Most Principal Architects either think strategically OR write code.
  Robin does both. Lead with this.
-->
<interview-positioning version="1.0" last-updated="2026-01-15">

  <!-- CORE NARRATIVE -->
  <narrative>
    <elevator-pitch>
      I architect programs for permanence. Every program I've built across three companies
      over 15 years is still running—the Stratozone program became Google Cloud Migration
      Center, the enablement standards I created at Google are embedded in their GTM process,
      the training program I built at McDonald's is being integrated into their Tech Academy.
      I'm also a builder-architect hybrid—I designed McDonald's enterprise AI architecture
      AND built the decision support tool that leadership uses for investment decisions.
      I can see the big picture, I can ship, and what I build lasts.
    </elevator-pitch>
    
    <differentiators>
      <differentiator id="builder-architect">
        <claim>Builder-Architect Hybrid</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>Decision support tool used by VP-CIO for AI investment decisions at McDonald's</proof>
          <proof>WaivePath 8-agent orchestration system built from scratch (React/Next.js, Firebase, Stripe)</proof>
          <proof>Food Network Windows 8 app (85% of production C# code for platform launch)</proof>
          <proof>Agentient multi-agent system with MCP server integration (Python, Cloud Run, Firebase)</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I can architect solutions I actually know how to build. My hands-on development
          at Agentient—Python, MCP integration, multi-agent orchestration—directly informs
          my enterprise architecture work at McDonald's."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>
      
      <differentiator id="zero-to-one">
        <claim>Zero-to-One Program Builder with 100% Survival Rate</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof survival="7+ years">SME for Stratozone acquisition → Google Cloud Migration Center (permanent product)</proof>
          <proof survival="6+ years">Value Engineering: scaled $150M → $1.5B pipeline (10X growth), program structure still in use</proof>
          <proof survival="3+ years">Industry Business Architecture: led 88 contributors, 12 industries → accreditation standard still in use</proof>
          <proof survival="active">GCP Champs: designed and led, 154 participants, 100 certifications → being integrated into Tech Academy</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I deliberately pursue emerging functions where I can build from zero.
          The trade-off is organizational volatility—these functions get restructured.
          The benefit is I build things that last even when my role doesn't. The Stratozone
          program I helped acquire became Google Cloud Migration Center—still in production
          seven years later. My survival rate is 100%: every major program I've built
          is still running."
        </talking-point>
        <survival-rate>100% across 6 programs, 3 companies, 15 years</survival-rate>
      </differentiator>
      
      <differentiator id="executive-access">
        <claim>Rapid Executive Engagement</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>Tribune: Workshop attendee → CEO presentation in weeks through self-initiated research</proof>
          <proof>AON: Competitive win against Google, invited to Rotterdam CTO conference</proof>
          <proof>McDonald's: CIO endorsed architecture as strategic direction, VP-CIO using decision support tool</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I research clients' strategic initiatives deeply before engaging.
          This consultative approach opens doors that pure sales can't reach."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>
      
      <differentiator id="ma-involvement">
        <claim>M&amp;A Strategic Contribution</claim>
        <evidence>
          <proof>Served as SME for Stratozone acquisition evaluation</proof>
          <proof>Conducted build vs. buy analysis; evaluated competing vendors</proof>
          <proof>Provided recommendation that informed acquisition decision—if negative, acquisition would not have proceeded</proof>
          <proof>Maintained CEO relationship that facilitated deal progression</proof>
          <proof>Product became Google Cloud Migration Center—still in production</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I served as the subject matter expert for Google Cloud's Stratozone acquisition.
          I conducted the build vs. buy analysis, evaluated competing vendors, and provided
          the recommendation that informed the decision. The product became Google Cloud
          Migration Center—still in production today."
        </talking-point>
      </differentiator>

      <differentiator id="permanence-architecture">
        <claim>Permanence Architecture: Programs That Outlast Tenure</claim>
        <methodology>
          <mechanism id="1">Standards Over Outputs: Create standards for how work gets done, not just content</mechanism>
          <mechanism id="2">Role Definition Creates Ownership: Define roles that make work someone's job</mechanism>
          <mechanism id="3">Institutional Anchoring: Attach programs to persistent structures (accreditations, academies, products)</mechanism>
          <mechanism id="4">Constituency Building at Scale: Scale participation to 100+ people who advocate for continuation</mechanism>
          <mechanism id="5">External Validation: Bring in external parties (consultants, partners, legal) for credibility</mechanism>
        </methodology>
        <evidence>
          <proof program="Stratozone" survival="7+ years">Became Google Cloud Migration Center—still in production</proof>
          <proof program="Industry BA" survival="3+ years">Became Level 300 accreditation standard—still in use</proof>
          <proof program="Enablement Standards" survival="3+ years">Integrated into GTM process for product launches</proof>
          <proof program="Value Engineering" survival="6+ years">Program structure adopted globally</proof>
          <proof program="Architecture Operating Model" survival="active">Adopted as McDonald's architecture standard</proof>
          <proof program="GCP Champs" survival="active">Being integrated into Global IT Tech Academy</proof>
        </evidence>
        <talking-point>
          "I don't just build programs—I architect them for permanence. Every program I've built
          across three companies over 15 years is still running today. I have a deliberate
          methodology: create standards rather than outputs, define roles that create ownership,
          anchor programs to institutional structures, build constituency at scale, and bring
          in external validation. The question isn't whether I can build something—it's whether
          it will survive without me. My track record says yes."
        </talking-point>
        <interview-response>
          "One thing I've learned building zero-to-one programs is that shipping is table stakes—
          survival is the differentiator. When I start a program, I'm simultaneously building
          the survival infrastructure: What standard is this creating? What role will own it?
          What institutional structure will it attach to? Who has invested enough to advocate
          for it? That's why the Stratozone program I built became Google Cloud Migration Center—
          still in production seven years later. That's why the training program I created at
          McDonald's is being integrated into the Global IT Tech Academy. I architect for permanence."
        </interview-response>
      </differentiator>
    </differentiators>
  </narrative>

  <!-- COMMON INTERVIEW QUESTIONS -->
  <common-questions>
    
    <question id="mcdonalds-tenure">
      <prompt>Tell me about your McDonald's work. What have you actually delivered?</prompt>
      <concern>Need to demonstrate concrete achievements with nearly two years tenure</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        McDonald's engaged me to design their AI platform architecture, which CIO endorsed
        as our strategic technical direction—implementation is now underway. But I also built
        working tools—the decision support tool that VP through CIO use to evaluate AI investment
        business cases, the GCP Champs program I designed and led with 154 participants and
        100 certifications. I believe architects should prove their designs work by building
        pieces of them.
      </recommended-response>
      <proof-points>
        <proof>10-layer architecture endorsed by CIO as strategic direction</proof>
        <proof>Decision support tool used by senior leadership (VP-CIO) for AI investment decisions</proof>
        <proof>GCP Champs: designed and led, 154 participants, 100 certifications, 7X completion rate</proof>
        <proof>Co-led 16 workshops; synthesized 325 use cases into 22 patterns, 10 submitted for funding</proof>
      </proof-points>
    </question>
    
    <question id="google-departures">
      <prompt>You had multiple role changes at Google. What happened?</prompt>
      <concern>Pattern of restructuring rather than advancement</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        Three transitions over seven years. First was a promotion—I moved into Head of
        Value Engineering when the org restructured. Second was my choice—I wanted to
        move into program management. Third was the 2023 layoff. For context, I had
        back-to-back Exceeds Expectations ratings in the prior two cycles—unusual at
        my level. My team was deprioritized, not my performance.
      </recommended-response>
      <reframe>
        "Restructured out" → "Promoted once, chose to move once, laid off as documented top performer"
      </reframe>
      <follow-up>
        "But here's what matters: the work lasted. Every program I built is still running.
        The Stratozone program became Google Cloud Migration Center—seven years and counting.
        The Industry BA program became the Level 300 accreditation standard—still in use.
        The enablement standards I created are embedded in Google's GTM process. I build
        institutions, not just initiatives. The role volatility is the cost of pursuing
        zero-to-one work; the permanence is what makes that cost worthwhile."
      </follow-up>
    </question>
    
    <question id="technical-depth">
      <prompt>Are you actually technical, or just a strategist who makes decks?</prompt>
      <concern>Principal Architect title often means paper architecture only</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I operate at whatever technical level solves the problem. At McDonald's, I use Copilot Studio and Power Automate for practical automation—the right tool for quick wins with leadership. At Agentient, I'm building custom MCP servers connecting Claude to Notion and filesystem, multi-agent orchestration in Python, RAG pipelines. I wrote 85% of the production code for the Food Network Windows 8 app—C# on a new platform with a hard deadline. The question isn't whether I can code—it's whether I choose the right technical approach for the problem.
      </recommended-response>
      <calibration-note>
        Technical depth ranges from lightweight to sophisticated:
        - Production code: Food Network app (C#, 85% of code, flagship launch)
        - Sophisticated architecture: Agentient (custom MCP servers, multi-agent orchestration, Python, RAG)
        - Practical low-code: McDonald's agents (Copilot Studio, Power Automate, Rovo)
        Position as "right tool for the problem" not "full-stack engineer." Don't conflate low-code automation with distributed systems engineering.
      </calibration-note>
    </question>
    
    <question id="pipeline-number">
      <prompt>You claim $1.5B pipeline. How do you attribute that to yourself?</prompt>
      <concern>Large numbers at big companies often reflect proximity, not causation</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        When I took over Value Engineering, my predecessor had built a partnership with 
        Stratozone running at about $150M pipeline. I made the decision to scale it globally—
        flew to 20 cities to train the sales force, renegotiated the partner contract to 
        add capabilities at no cost, and reinvested savings into the enablement program. 
        I also consolidated a second partner (CloudPhysics) under the same umbrella. 
        In 9 months, the program scaled to $1.5B. The causal chain is clear: I built the 
        infrastructure that enabled the field to qualify and quantify deals at scale.
      </recommended-response>
      <better-framing>
        "Scaled Google Cloud's value engineering program from $150M to $1.5B pipeline (10X growth) 
        by training the global sales force across 20 cities, renegotiating partner contracts, 
        and standardizing TCO methodology."
      </better-framing>
    </question>
    
    <question id="tribune-opportunity">
      <prompt>You mention a $3.3B opportunity that didn't close. How is that an achievement?</prompt>
      <concern>Claiming credit for deals that didn't happen</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        The $3.3B demonstrates capability, not outcome. My job was business development—
        identify opportunities, secure executive access, build strategic cases. I went from 
        a technical workshop to CEO presentation within weeks through self-initiated market 
        research. The tablet deal didn't close due to device quality issues outside my control. 
        What I did convert was a major Windows Azure partnership that saved Tribune $1.5M 
        annually. The Azure deal was the actual win; the tablet opportunity shows how I find 
        and pursue strategic possibilities.
      </recommended-response>
      <better-framing>
        "Identified $3.3B tablet partnership opportunity through self-initiated market analysis; 
        secured CEO presentation within weeks. Converted relationship into Windows Azure 
        partnership with $1.5M annual cost savings."
      </better-framing>
    </question>
    
    <question id="venture-experience">
      <prompt>Your startup ventures don't seem successful. Why should I value that experience?</prompt>
      <concern>Founder titles without market success</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        WaivePath taught me hard lessons about go-to-market—we built for salespeople who
        don't buy learning products instead of sales enablement professionals who do.
        I also learned about partnership dynamics—we had disagreements about direction,
        I was outvoted, the pivot failed. Now I own 100% of Agentient so partner dynamics
        can't derail execution. The technical work was real: 8-agent orchestration system,
        React/Next.js frontend, Firebase backend, Stripe payments—shipped to market.
        The hands-on development keeps my technical skills sharp, which makes me a better
        enterprise architect.
      </recommended-response>
      <reframe>
        "Failed startup" → "Shipped product, learned hard lessons about GTM and partnerships I'm now applying"
      </reframe>
    </question>
    
    <question id="325-use-cases">
      <prompt>What does "325 use cases" actually mean?</prompt>
      <concern>Large numbers might be superficial taxonomy work</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I participated as a core member of discovery workshops across 8 business functions—
        16 workshops total, 2 per function. From those workshops, we identified 325 potential
        AI use cases. I then synthesized findings to identify common patterns, consolidating
        them into 22 reusable architectural patterns. 10 of those patterns have been submitted
        for funding. The use cases are substantial—in fact, we need to break them down into
        more manageable implementation chunks.
      </recommended-response>
      <better-framing>
        "Co-led AI opportunity discovery across 8 business functions through 16 workshops;
        synthesized 325 use cases into 22 reusable architectural patterns, 10 of which
        are now submitted for funding."
      </better-framing>
    </question>
    
    <question id="88-contributors">
      <prompt>You say you "managed" 88 people. Did you actually manage them?</prompt>
      <concern>Overclaiming authority</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        Let me be precise: I led a cross-functional program with 88 contributors across 
        10 workstreams through Google's 20% project framework. I recruited, coordinated, 
        and provided performance feedback, but I had no hire/fire authority or budget. 
        The achievement was achieving results through influence rather than positional power—
        which is often harder than direct management.
      </recommended-response>
      <correction>
        Always say "led" not "managed" for this program.
      </correction>
    </question>

  <question id="side-company">
      <prompt>What about your side company? Will that be a distraction?</prompt>
      <concern>Moonlighting may signal divided attention</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I've been transparent about Principio Group with every employer. I negotiated
        moonlighting rights at McDonald's and I'd want to discuss the same here. The work
        is evenings and weekends, it doesn't compete with [Company], and frankly it keeps
        my technical skills sharp in ways that benefit my day job. If it's a dealbreaker,
        I'm open to discussing options, but I've found most companies see the value in
        architects who actually build things.
      </recommended-response>
      <note>
        Google generally allows moonlighting. Microsoft or McKinsey may be stricter.
        Be prepared to surrender if compensation and opportunity are compelling enough.
      </note>
    </question>

    <question id="why-leaving-mcdonalds">
      <prompt>Why are you leaving McDonald's?</prompt>
      <concern>Short tenure or negative framing could raise red flags</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        McDonald's is going through significant organizational changes, and I'm looking
        to return to tier-one tech where I can work at the pace and scale I experienced
        at Google. I've delivered what I came to do—the AI architecture, the decision
        support tools, the training program—and I'm ready for the next challenge.
      </recommended-response>
      <never-say>
        "McDonald's is not an efficient organization" or "I joined for income to sustain my startup"
      </never-say>
    </question>

    <question id="program-survival">
      <prompt>How do you ensure programs survive after you leave?</prompt>
      <concern>Programs often collapse when their champion departs</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I've developed a deliberate methodology for this—I call it permanence architecture.
        Five things: First, I create standards, not just outputs. Standards become how work
        gets done and can be enforced without me. Second, I define roles that make the work
        someone's job—they have incentive to protect it. Third, I anchor programs to
        institutional structures that persist—accreditation programs, training academies,
        products with P&amp;L owners. Fourth, I build constituency at scale—when 300 people
        have been trained or certified, no single executive can kill it. Fifth, I bring in
        external validation—Accenture, McKinsey, legal requirements—that creates credibility
        independent of me.

        The proof is the track record: Stratozone became Google Cloud Migration Center,
        still in production seven years later. The Industry BA program became a Level 300
        accreditation requirement. The enablement standards are embedded in Google's GTM
        process. Every major program I've built is still running.
      </recommended-response>
      <proof-points>
        <proof>Stratozone → Google Cloud Migration Center (7+ years)</proof>
        <proof>Industry BA → Level 300 accreditation standard (3+ years)</proof>
        <proof>Enablement standards → GTM process (3+ years)</proof>
        <proof>Value Engineering → global program structure (6+ years)</proof>
        <proof>GCP Champs → Tech Academy integration (active)</proof>
      </proof-points>
    </question>

    <question id="management-gap">
      <prompt>You don't have much management experience. How would you lead a team?</prompt>
      <concern>Limited direct reports (88 via influence, 3 startup, 10 early career), no budget authority in most roles</concern>
      <recommended-response>
        I'm a builder, not an operator—and that's intentional. I create things that BECOME teams, then hire leaders for those teams. My 0-1 skills are different from management skills. I've led 88 contributors through influence, conducted ~100 Google interviews showing people assessment capability, and managed 10 consultants early career at Revere. But my differentiator is building institutions that outlast me, not managing steady-state operations. Many companies have plenty of managers but few builders.
      </recommended-response>
      <reframe>"Management gap" → "Builder-not-operator pattern that selects OUT of time-consuming management incompatible with innovation work"</reframe>
      <proof-points>
        <proof>88 contributors led via influence (no hire/fire authority)</proof>
        <proof>~100 Google interviews conducted (people assessment)</proof>
        <proof>10 consultants managed at Revere Group</proof>
        <proof>6 programs built that became teams (hired operators to run them)</proof>
      </proof-points>
    </question>

  </common-questions>

  <!-- VULNERABILITY HANDLING -->
  <vulnerabilities>
    
    <vulnerability id="role-volatility">
      <concern>Pattern of roles ending via restructure rather than advancement</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        True. Zero-to-one roles in emerging functions are inherently volatile. 
        This is a deliberate trade-off, not a failure pattern.
      </honest-assessment>
      <reframe>
        "I deliberately pursue zero-to-one opportunities in emerging functions, knowing
        they'll restructure. The trade-off is role volatility; the benefit is I build
        institutions, not just initiatives. My survival rate is 100%—every program I've
        built is still running. The Stratozone program became Google Cloud Migration Center.
        The enablement standards I created were adopted across Google Cloud GTM. The
        architecture operating model at McDonald's will guide the organization for years.
        The question isn't how long was I in the role—it's whether what I built lasted.
        It always does."
      </reframe>
      <proof-of-lasting-impact>
        <proof>Stratozone → Google Cloud Migration Center (permanent product)</proof>
        <proof>Industry BA program → Principal Architect Level 300 accreditation</proof>
        <proof>Enablement standards → adopted across GTM</proof>
      </proof-of-lasting-impact>
    </vulnerability>
    
    <vulnerability id="mcdonalds-paper-architecture">
      <concern>10-layer architecture is not implemented; it's a strategic target state</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        True. Architecture was endorsed by CIO as strategic direction, but implementation
        is just beginning. This is a 2-3 year roadmap.
      </honest-assessment>
      <mitigation>
        Lead with decision support tool that's running and used by leadership.
        Frame architecture as "endorsed as strategic direction, implementation underway."
      </mitigation>
      <talking-point>
        "I designed the 10-layer architecture that CIO endorsed as McDonald's strategic
        technical direction. Implementation is now underway. What's running today is the
        decision support tool that senior leadership uses for AI investment decisions."
      </talking-point>
    </vulnerability>
    
    <vulnerability id="technical-depth-calibration">
      <concern>McDonald's agents are low-code (Copilot Studio), not sophisticated engineering</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        True. Copilot Studio and Power Automate are citizen developer tools. 
        Don't conflate with building distributed systems.
      </honest-assessment>
      <calibration>
        Technical depth ranges from:
        - Production code (Food Network app, C#)
        - Sophisticated system architecture (Agentient, MCP, multi-agent)
        - Practical low-code automation (McDonald's agents)
        Position as "operating at whatever level solves the problem."
      </calibration>
    </vulnerability>
    
    <vulnerability id="venture-traction">
      <concern>Founder titles without commercial success</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        WaivePath has limited traction—wrong target segment, partnership disagreements.
        Agentient is in early beta, still acquiring users. Don't overclaim.
      </honest-assessment>
      <reframe>
        "Founder who shipped product, learned hard lessons about GTM and partner
        selection, applying those lessons to current work. Now own 100% of Agentient
        so partner dynamics can't derail execution."
      </reframe>
    </vulnerability>

    <vulnerability id="decision-tool-low-code">
      <concern>Decision Support Tool is low-code (Copilot Studio), not sophisticated engineering</concern>
      <honest-assessment>
        High visibility, used by VP-CIO for AI investment decisions, but technically low-code citizen developer tool (Copilot Studio, Power Automate). Scrutiny risk if positioned as deep technical work.
      </honest-assessment>
      <mitigation>
        Don't lead with this when technical depth questioned. Pivot to:
        (1) ServiceNow RAG solution (hands-on solution architecture)
        (2) Agentient development (custom MCP servers, multi-agent orchestration in Python)
        (3) Prompt engineering expertise (demonstrable craft)
      </mitigation>
      <talking-point>
        "At McDonald's, I use Copilot Studio and Power Automate for practical automation—the right tool for the problem. At Agentient, I'm building custom MCP servers and multi-agent orchestration in Python. I operate at whatever technical level solves the problem."
      </talking-point>
    </vulnerability>

  </vulnerabilities>

  <!-- NUMBERS THAT SURVIVE SCRUTINY -->
  <quantification-guide>
    
    <metric id="pipeline-1.5b" defensibility="high">
      <claim>$1.5B pipeline in 9 months</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        Inherited $150M run-rate → scaled globally via training (20 cities) + 
        partner consolidation + contract renegotiation → 10X growth
      </causal-chain>
      <better-framing>
        "Scaled from $150M to $1.5B" (shows baseline and growth)
      </better-framing>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="stratozone-acquisition" defensibility="high">
      <claim>Served as SME for acquisition that became Google Cloud Migration Center</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        SME for evaluation → build vs. buy analysis → evaluated competing vendors →
        provided recommendation that informed decision (if negative, wouldn't have proceeded) →
        maintained CEO relationship → acquisition closed
      </causal-chain>
      <note>This is undersold. Should be headline of Google section. Product still in production.</note>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="tribune-3.3b" defensibility="medium">
      <claim>$3.3B opportunity identified</claim>
      <issue>Deal didn't close. Opportunity identification ≠ achievement.</issue>
      <reframe>
        Lead with capability (CEO access in weeks) and actual win (Azure deal, $1.5M savings).
        Use $3.3B to demonstrate strategic thinking scope, not as outcome.
      </reframe>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="use-cases-325" defensibility="medium">
      <claim>325 AI use cases analyzed</claim>
      <issue>"Analyzed" is ambiguous. Could mean taxonomy or deep design.</issue>
      <clarification>
        Portfolio synthesis + pattern extraction (22 patterns), not 325 individual technical designs.
      </clarification>
      <reframe>
        "Synthesized 325 use cases into 22 reusable architectural patterns"
      </reframe>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="contributors-88" defensibility="high">
      <claim>88 contributors across 10 workstreams</claim>
      <issue>Were not direct reports. Volunteer 20% project.</issue>
      <correction>
        Say "led" not "managed." The achievement is influence without authority.
      </correction>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="gcp-champs" defensibility="high">
      <claim>Designed and led: 154 direct + 166 pull-through, 100 certifications, 7X completion rate</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        Designed program → led implementation → measured outcomes from reports
      </causal-chain>
      <note>CIO praised program; being integrated into Global IT Tech Academy. Robin designed AND led this—full credit.</note>
    </metric>
    
    <metric id="decision-support-tool" defensibility="high">
      <claim>Decision support tool used by senior leadership (VP-CIO) for AI investment decisions</claim>
      <calibration>
        Real and running, used regularly by senior directors, VPs, through CIO.
        Interrogates McDonald's central initiative tracking repository—one of most critical repos.
      </calibration>
      <reframe>
        Lead with this. "Built decision support tool used by senior leadership for
        AI investment decisions" is concrete and impressive.
      </reframe>
    </metric>

    <metric id="program-survival-rate" defensibility="high">
      <claim>100% program survival rate: 6 programs across 3 companies, all running 3-7+ years post-departure</claim>
      <causal-chain>
        Deliberate methodology applied at program inception → standards created → roles defined →
        institutional anchors established → constituency built at scale → external validation secured →
        programs persist independent of original champion
      </causal-chain>
      <evidence>
        <program name="Stratozone" company="Google" years="7+">Became Google Cloud Migration Center—production product</program>
        <program name="Industry BA" company="Google" years="3+">Became Level 300 accreditation standard</program>
        <program name="Enablement Standards" company="Google" years="3+">Integrated into GTM process</program>
        <program name="Value Engineering" company="Google" years="6+">Program structure adopted globally</program>
        <program name="Architecture Operating Model" company="McDonald's" years="active">Adopted as standard</program>
        <program name="GCP Champs" company="McDonald's" years="active">Being integrated into Tech Academy</program>
      </evidence>
      <talking-point>
        "The differentiating question isn't 'did you build it'—it's 'is it still running?'
        My answer is yes, every time."
      </talking-point>
    </metric>

  </quantification-guide>

  <!-- THINGS TO NEVER SAY -->
  <never-say>
    <item reason="Self-assessment that sounds arrogant">
      "I'm the most knowledgeable person on AI at McDonald's"
    </item>
    <item reason="Reveals misaligned priorities">
      "McDonald's is just my income source; my passion is elsewhere"
    </item>
    <item reason="Conflates low-code with software engineering">
      "I deployed AI agents across McDonald's enterprise" (they're small-scale experiments)
    </item>
    <item reason="Claims outcome that didn't happen">
      "I achieved a $3.3B deal at Microsoft" (opportunity, not win)
    </item>
    <item reason="Overclaims authority">
      "I managed 88 people at Google" (led program, no hire/fire)
    </item>
    <item reason="Paper architecture isn't achievement at Principal level">
      "CIO approved my strategy document" (what's implemented?)
    </item>
    <item reason="Undersells the permanence differentiator">
      "My programs were successful" without specifying survival evidence—the claim is
      about permanence, not launch. Always quantify: "still running X years later"
    </item>
  </never-say>

  <!-- POSITIVE REFRAMES -->
  <always-say>
    <item context="When discussing Agentient alongside corporate work">
      "I build AI systems professionally and personally. The hands-on work keeps 
      my technical skills sharp, which makes me a better architect."
    </item>
    <item context="When discussing venture experience">
      "I shipped a product, learned hard lessons about market validation and partner 
      selection, and I'm applying those lessons to my current work."
    </item>
    <item context="When discussing Google role changes">
      "I deliberately pursue zero-to-one opportunities. The Stratozone program I 
      built became Google Cloud Migration Center—I build things that last."
    </item>
    <item context="When asked about technical depth">
      "I operate at whatever technical level solves the problem—from production code
      to sophisticated agent architectures to practical automation."
    </item>
    <item context="When asked about role changes or program longevity">
      "I build things that survive. The question isn't 'did you build it'—it's 'is it
      still running?' Stratozone became Google Cloud Migration Center—seven years and
      counting. The enablement standards I created are still embedded in Google's GTM
      process. My survival rate is 100%."
    </item>
  </always-say>

</interview-positioning>
